<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE reference PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Reference//EN" "technicalContent/dtd/reference.dtd" [
]>



<reference id = "id16BNL0Y03NZ"
    xmlns:ditaarch = "http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<title>Allied Tribes of America</title>
<shortdesc>Native American alliance</shortdesc>
<prolog></prolog>
<refbody><section><ul><li><b>Core Membership:</b> Grey Owl, Scorpion,
Stevie Whitefire</li>
<li><b>Former Members:</b> None known.</li>
<li><b>Affiliates:</b> Stormshadow (deceased)</li>
<li><b>Base of Operations:</b> New Mexico</li>
<li><b>Primary Goal:</b> Representation and protection of Native
Americans</li>
<li><b>First Appearance:</b> Offspring #1 (first mention), Blood
Brothers Vol. 2 #? (first shown)</li>
<li><b>Status:</b> Active</li></ul></section>
<section><title>Description:</title><p>The Allied Tribes of America
is a group dedicated to preserving and defending the way of life
of Native Americans across North America. The current Chief of the
Alliance is Grey Owl.</p></section>
<section><title>History:</title><p>The first mention of the Allied
Tribes of America was by Stevie Whitefire in his role as ambassador
for the Tribes to the Holy War peace talks in Berlin. Stevie had
been dispatched to the talks in order to gain some awareness from
the factions involved in the Holy War that there was full-blown
genocide against the Native American population of Canada. Unfortunately, the
Earth Alliance (EA) would not recognize Stevie’s ambassadorial claims,
and so relegated him to the observer’s galleries where he went on
to meet the other members of the Offspring.</p><p>The PSF (see Blood
Brothers) had a run-in with some members of the Allied Tribes in
2014, when they were called in to escort Gabriella Alvarez off American
soil. As she was a guest of Stevie Whitefire and the Tribes, this
did not go over well. However, she did consent to leave the US and
everyone parted ways without a fight.</p><p>The Allied Tribes have
become allies with the Faerie as they decided they had many common
interests during the Holy War. This alliance still stands despite
the end of the Holy War.</p><p>The Allied Tribes of America were
created by Braz King.</p>.</section></refbody></reference>
