<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE reference PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Reference//EN" "technicalContent/dtd/reference.dtd" [
]>



<reference id = "id16BNKK00EK5"
    xmlns:ditaarch = "http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<title>Afrikaners Meta- Human Defense Battalion</title>
<shortdesc>Super Team</shortdesc>
<refbody><section><ul><li><b>Core Membership:</b> Firearms (leader,
deceased),Efferfran (deceased), Moonbeam (incarcerated), Cavalier
II, Firestar (deceased)</li>
<li><b>Mercenary Members:</b> Bludgeon, Vagabond</li>
<li><b>Affiliates:</b>Technomancer (technician)</li>
<li><b>Base of Operations:</b>Cape Town, South Africa</li>
<li><b>Primary Goal:</b> Defense of South Africa from internal and
external threats.</li>
<li><b>First Appearance:</b> Classic Comics Team- Up #17</li>
<li><b>Status:</b> Inactive</li></ul></section>
<section><title>Description:</title><p>Created just before the Horde
Invasion, the Afrikaners Meta- Human Defense Battalion (AMDB) is
modeled after the successful Canadian MetaForce. It has the job
of defending South Africa and its people from internal and external
threats - especially those which include paranormals or the Horde
. Their secret agenda includes maintaining the racial status quo
in South Africa and to ensure that no paranormals arise in the black
population. Many members, Efferfran most notably, have secret agendas
of their own.</p></section>
<section><title>History:</title><p>The Afrikaners Meta- Human Defense
Battalion were instrumental in maintaining order in South Africa
following the Horde Invasion. Despite repeated requests from the
Earth Alliance, the AMDB did not aid in the campaigns against the
Horde “nations”. South Africa maintains they must be given ‘veto’
powers in the Earth Alliance (EA) before their meta- human assets are
forced to risk their lives for the EA..The team first came to the
attention of the paranormal community when they invaded Arcadia
with the help of the South African regular army. This attack was
foiled by the unlikely grouping of Spellbinder, Runewolf and Nightdemon.</p><p>Enforcers
Inc. then met the AMDB when they were called in by one of the Enforcer
member countries to help protect their boarder. A group of black
paranormals were attempting to flee South Africa over the boarder,
but the AMDB caught up to them and slaughtered the entire group.
The Enforcers could do nothing but sit and watch. A deep hatred
between Rumble and Firearms was born at this point.</p><p>Enforcers
Inc. then met the AMDB when they were called in by one of the Enforcer
member countries to help protect their boarder. A group of black
paranormals were attempting to flee South Africa over the boarder,
but the AMDB caught up to them and slaughtered the entire group.
The Enforcers could do nothing but sit and watch. A deep hatred
between Rumble and Firearms was born at this point.</p><p>Rob Scearce
created the Afrikaaners Metahuman Defense Battalion.</p></section>
<section></section></refbody></reference>
