<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA 1.3 Concept//EN" "technicalContent/dtd/concept.dtd" [
]>



<concept id = "id16C8M0UH0VY"
    xmlns:ditaarch = "http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<title>Atlanteans</title>
<shortdesc>Atlanteans are divided into two categories, Atlanteans
and True Atlanteans.</shortdesc>
<conbody><section><title>Atlanteans</title><b>Description</b> <p>A
race of aquatic humanoids living at the bottom of Earth’s oceans.
They are an insular, self absorbed culture that usually have little
or no contact with humanity. The few exceptions to this have almost
always been violent encounters. These Atlanteans are distantly related
to the true Atlanteans destroyed by the Protectors in the year 38,
000 BC. Those true Atlanteans consider these people to be ‘genetic
scum’ and ‘primitive deviants’.</p><p><b>History</b></p><p>The race
of Atlanteans rarely deal with humanity. The exceptions to this
are during the time of ancient Greece where they carried on a brief
trade with daring merchants. Another, better documented encounter
occurred immediately before the Quintessential Incident. The Atlanteans
were lead by an usuper king to invade the surface world. Eventually
the king was deposed and the invasion ended.</p><p>In April of 1997,
the Assailants were credited with attacking and massacring all the
citizens of Atlantis. There is only one survivor of this race, the
woman known as Breaker.</p></section>
<section><title>True Atlanteans</title><p><b>Description</b></p><p>True
Atlanteans are a race that flourished on the now sunken continent
of Atlantis, 40, 000 years ago. Very little now remains of their
culture and civilization. True Atlanteans stand 8.5 feet tall and
are extremely thin and graceful. They have sharp features with long
noses and chins and pointed ears. They dress in long flowing, gauze-
like robes of pale colours. They have admitted a kinship to the
Faerie, but what that kinship is remains uncertain. They are disgusted
by the water-beings who call themselves Atlanteans, but they may
also have some relationship to them as well.</p><p><b>History</b></p><p>Atlanteans
existed long before the appearance of Homo Sapiens. The Atlantean
culture flourished on the continent of Atlantis and ended after
the appearance of Cro- Magnon man. They had trade with other planets
in other solar systems and produced works of art undreamed of by
modern artists.</p><p>The Atlantean civilization was ended forever
by the arrival of the alien Protectors. The Protectors destroyed
the continent of Atlantis and all but three of the Atlanteans. These
three, called the Sleepers, managed to entrap the Protector Leader
for 40, 000 years. The Sleepers came into contact with Homo Sapiens
for the first time in April, 1999, when Enforcers Inc. first discovered
the Atlanteans lost city.</p><p>In Jan. 2000, the Atlanteans were
finally avenged as the Protectors were themselves destroyed.</p><p>Kel
McKay created the Atlanteans and Rob Scearce created the True Atlanteans.</p></section></conbody></concept>
