<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA 1.3 Concept//EN" "technicalContent/dtd/concept.dtd" [
]>



<concept id = "id16BPF0D0XI1"
    xmlns:ditaarch = "http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<title>American Eagles</title>
<shortdesc>American Super Team</shortdesc>
<conbody><ul><li><b>Core Membership:</b> Golden Eagle (leader), King Fisher </li>
<li><b>Former Members:</b> Ironhawk (executed), Roc (deceased)</li>
<li><b>Affiliates:</b> Society for Advanced Beings, Evolutionary Party</li>
<li><b>Base of Operations:</b> Unknown, somewhere in the continetal United States</li>
<li><b>Primary Goal:</b> Protect the POTUS and other threats to high level U.S. govenment</li>
<li><b>First Appearance:</b> Blood Brothers #4</li>
<li><b>Status:</b> Active</li></ul>
<section><title>Description:</title>
<p>The American Eagles, once called the Firebirds, are the personal, paranormal bodyguards of the President of the United States. They were once a 
	sub- faction of the Society for Advanced Beings. As this was blatantly illegal, they lobbied for their current position. They are of the belief 
	that paranormals are inherently superior to normal humans. They refer to normal humans as either ‘feebles’ or ‘ancestors’. The members of the 
	Firebirds are all members of the Society for Advanced Beings as well as the Evolutionary Party.</p>
	</section>
	<section><title>History</title>
	<p>The first known action of the American Eagles, then known as the Firebirds, was an attempt to capture the Orbital Laser Cannon (OLC) from the control of the Sons of Freedom. 
		They encountered the Blood Brothers and fought to a standstill until the Firebirds were made to believe that Elemental had destroyed the 
		OLC. The Firebirds retreated at this point.</p>
		<p>The Firebirds were active during the Second American Civil War in Jan. 1998. During this incident, Roc was killed when he attacked a dozen 
			F- 15 fighter bombers. Kingfisher was wounded but returned to duty after the war. After the election of President Gordon Lantern Page, 
			the members of the Firebirds served in several key administrative positions. Later, when their position as a paramilitary arm of a 
			political party became a problem, they were given the post of Presidential Bodyguards. This is when they became the American Eagles.</p>
			<p>Braz King created the American Eagles.</p></section></conbody></concept>
