<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA 1.3 Concept//EN" "technicalContent/dtd/concept.dtd" [
]>



<concept id = "id16C8M700VKF"><title>Avatar</title>
<shortdesc>Alien Invader</shortdesc>
<conbody><section><title>Description</title>
<p>Avatar is an ancient being capable of living unaided in space and traveling interstellar distances. 
Avatar greatly resembled a giant starfish and was estimated to be almost a mile across. Avatar’s sex has never 
been determined (although feminists like to claim that is was male). It has also never been determined wether or 
not Avatar was a unique being. Avatar could project vast amounts of pure energy that is apparently generated within 
itself and was immune to anything less than a nuclear detonation. Its only known weakness was a vulnerability to 
magical energies, although given Avatar’s strength, this weakness made little difference.</p></section>
<section><title>History</title>
<p>Avatar was a ravager of worlds. It destroyed worlds out of the sheer pleasure of destruction. Eons ago, Avatar came 
upon a planet, the name of which has been lost to memory, and devastated the peaceful population. The lone survivor of 
this massacre was a being who later gave himself the name of Custodiax. Custodiax took it upon himself to halt Avatar’s 
deadly rampage.</p>
<p>Custodiax made his stand when Avatar approached the planet Earth. Custodiax was successful and Avatar retreated. 
Being a patient being of destruction, Avatar slept for 5,000 years until he felt the death of Custodiax approaching.
When Custodiax finally died of old age, Avatar was finally free to destroy Earth.</p>
<p>In March of 1989, Avatar traveled the globe, leaving a trail of destruction in its wake. The paranormals of Earth attempted 
to stop Avatar, but they were largely unsuccessful. Avatar killed over one billion people all over the globe. This included the 
following known paranormals: Basher, Black Diamond, Blue Ghost, Buzz Alum, Firelord, Ironguard, Jackal- Wolf, Jerry Greycloud, 
Leech, Lektron, Link, Moonshadow I, Panzer I, Rockhead, Siren, Solarblast, Tarantula and Visionary.</p>
<p>Avatar was eventually driven from Earth by the combined might of Earth’s superbeings. However, it then used its control over 
the fabric of the universe to transport all of Earth’s paranormals to Mars, where many of them proceeded to suffocate. Luckily 
for everyone, Solarblast got his hands on a mystical device known as the Artifact and used it to obliterate Avatar at the cost 
of his own life. All the paranormals peaceably returned to Earth aboard Transformer I. </p>
<p>A new twist to the mystery of Avatar was revealed when Sun Worshipper spotted Zenith (a member of the Hit Men). 
Zenith appears to be a miniature version of Avatar...</p>
<p>Kel McKay created Avatar.</p></section></conbody></concept>
