<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE reference PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Reference//EN" "technicalContent/dtd/reference.dtd">



<reference><title>Altair Industries</title>
<shortdesc>Corporation Report </shortdesc><prolog></prolog>
<refbody><section><ul><li><b>Principal Investors:</b> Synertech (74%), Chris Connolly (% 5), Olympus Corp (7%),
Various Altair Ind. employees (% 14)
</li>
<li><b>Affiliates:</b> Unified Projects Amalgamated (Australia)</li>
<li><b>Headquarters:</b> Bonn, Germany</li>
<li><b>Primary Goal:</b> Research, production and marketing of high- tech electronics.</li>
<li><b>Status:</b> Active</li></ul></section>
<section><title>Description:</title>
<p>Altair Industries (AI) was once a purveyor of high quality arms. However, since 1989, their emphasis has shifted away from arms and into high- tech electronics. AI specializes in both telecommunication and spy satellites, control systems, computers (particularly in the field of parallel- processing), cybernetics and virtual realities.</p>
<p>The corporation is run as a family affair, first by Frederick Altair and then by his son Jeremy. Mostly due to the economic hard times, many of the company employees were forced to sell their stock in the company. Much of that stock was bought up by Synertech during that time.</p>
</section>
<section><title>History:</title>
<p>Altair Industries was incorporated in Bonn, West Germany in 1975 by Frederick Altair. Most of the company’s contracts were war products to NATO - primarily electronics equipment, but also included custom computers, satellites and guidance systems. This continued until the death of Frederick in 1989. Jeremy (see Cyber I), Frederick’s son, took over the company at the age of 19 and immediately decided to change the focus of the company from the weapons field. The change created great tension among the researchers of the company as some products were abruptly closed down and new ones started. Some of the researchers quit as their pet projects were cancelled, but those who stayed formed the core of the company’s new ‘family’, and over time, new researchers replaced those who left.</p>
<p>Altair Industries is the only company currently producing Skillsofts (TM) - an electronic implant that provides useful skills to its user. While still in its novelty stages, they have been able to utilize much of the same technology to produce their ‘mental block implant’. This device is much in demand among career diplomats and such</p>
<p>Altair Industries current project is a device that would allow the transmission of images directly to the human brain. While still incomplete, Altair expects to have a prototype ready by 1999. Recently, Altair Industries has devoted a large portion of their resources to Unified Projects Amalgamated, a move that has lead many people to believe that AI is in a vulnerable position. This has lead the company to try and safeguard their assets in the event of a hostile takeover. Indeed, this prompted SynerTech to launch a bid in 1996 to take over the company. Although this take- over attempt was ultimately a failure, Altair Industries has had to cut back their research budgets to the minimum in order to protect the company from predators.</p>
<p>After the death of Jeremy Altair during the Horde Invasion, the company stock was transferred over to the German Government, who offered it to the highest bidder. Through a series of back room deals and a substantial cash payment, the stock was sold to SynerTech, which now holds a comfortable majority of stock. Altair Industries was badly damaged during the Horde Invasion, and it will be many years before it is back up to its former level of production and profit.</p>
<p>Jason Blackthorn created Altair Industries and Rob Scearce contributed to it.</p></section></refbody>
</reference>
