<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA 1.3 Concept//EN" "technicalContent/dtd/concept.dtd" [
]>



<concept id = "id16C8L0M02T8"><title>Arista Corp</title>
<shortdesc>Corporation Report</shortdesc>

<conbody><section><ul><li><b>Principal Investors:</b> Jed Stevens (33%), Linda M. Little- Hughes (32%), Olympus
Corp (5%)</li>
<li><b>Affiliates:</b> ViaChem, Listen Manufacturing, Exxon, Optix Inc.</li>
<li><b>Headquaters:</b> Dallas, Texas, USA</li>
<li><b>Primary Goal:</b> Increase returns to shareholders.</li>
<li><b>Status:</b> Active</li></ul></section>
<section><title>Description</title>
<p>Arista Corp. is a massive conglomerate comprised of hundreds of member companies ranging from forestry to textiles, from mining to high finance. 
Some of the companies under the Arista Corp. umbrella are ViaChem, Listen Manufacturing, Exxon and Optix Incorporated.</p></section>
<section><title>History</title>
<p>Jed Stevens, a Wall Street investor (and jazz aficionado) formed Aristocrat Investments in 1935. The company survived the Great Depression and 
emerged as one of the most powerful financial forces in America. Although Jed is a very honourable man, several scheming individuals have worked 
their way into powerful positions in the company, pushing the aged Jed into a figurehead position.</p>
<p>In 1989, research began to create powered armor for use by the company. Two different designs are currently operative; Iron Guard I (1995) 
and Iron Guard II (1996). A third design, the Iron Guard III, is rumoured to be near completion.</p>
<p>In 1998, the company won a bid for the construction of the mass- produced Power Trooper Battle armor, first from the UN and then, after the Horde Invasion, 
from the EA. The Power.Trooper Baltimore allows an infantry soldier to survive a direct hit from a Horde weapon, causing a great demand for the armor.</p>
<p>Since the Horde Invasion in November 1998, the company has suffered from power shortages as well as substantial repair costs. While this is offset by an 
increase in orders for their weapons and armor systems, it will likely be several years until their production is back to pre- invasion levels.</p>
<p>Braz King created Arista Corp.</p></section></conbody></concept>
