<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA 1.3 Concept//EN" "technicalContent/dtd/concept.dtd" [
]>



<concept id = "id16BPG04N0YM"
    xmlns:ditaarch = "http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<title>Amethia</title>
<shortdesc><b>Planetary Report</b></shortdesc>

<conbody><p><ul><li><b>Primary Star:</b> Alpha Centari (G2 V- yellow, main sequence)</li>
<li><b>Stellar Co- ordinates:</b> -27.0, 5.0, -11. 2 (4. 25 ly from Earth 55APs)</li>
<li><b>Orbital Period:</b> N/ A (Earth = 365.256 days)</li>
<li><b>Rotational Period:</b> N/ A (Earth = 23h, 56m, 4.1s)</li>
<li><b>Tilt of Axis:</b> N/ A (Earth = 23^ 27’)</li>
<li><b>Diameter:</b> N/ A (Earth = 7, 915 miles)</li>
<li><b>Mass:</b> N/ A (Earth = 1. 000)</li>
<li><b>Density:</b> N/ A (Earth = 5. 517 grams/ cm3)</li>
<li><b>Surface Gravity:</b> 1.802 (Earth = 1.000)</li>
<li><b>Escape Velocity:</b> 16 APs (Earth = 15 APs)</li>
<li><b>Surface Temperature:</b> N/ A (Earth = 200- 300 K)</li>
<li><b>Satellites:</b> N/A</li></ul></p>
<section><title>Description</title>
<p>Amethia is a world with higher- than- Earth gravity as well as a light oxygen atmosphere. The planet is not well suited for the propagation 
	of life as seen in its primary inhabitants who number less than 50,000 individuals. These metal- based life- forms ‘eat’ ultra- violet light, 
	‘breath’ through photosynthesis and have a high degree of physical adaptability. They are very tolerant of differing social norms.</p>
	</section>
	<section><title>History</title><p>Two Amethites have been encountered by other races so far. The first was Hissalana, an Agent of the Keepers of 
		Cosmic Order, encountered by the time jumping Regulators, 2,400.years ago. The second was Violet, the champion of Amethia who was 
		encountered by Ameryllis and Cyber I. </p>
		<p>In 2015, a dead Amethite was discovered by Shadowcaster, Predator, Psiforce and The Blue Man on a space faring vessel that greatly resembled 
			the old World Force sattelite. This Amethite was discovered to have been used by the Horde to create the Psionic Insanity Virus that 
			devestated Lamaris and would’ve devestated Earth had it not been for Enforcers Inc. It was also discovered that the Amethite was a 
			‘no-mana zone’ and the Blue Man had a vision of it fighting against the Horde.</p>
			<p>Kel McKay created the planet of Amethia.</p></section></conbody></concept>
 
