<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA 1.3 Concept//EN" "technicalContent/dtd/concept.dtd" [
]>



<concept id = "id16BSA000002"
    xmlns:ditaarch = "http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<title>Arcadia</title>
<shortdesc>Dimension</shortdesc>
<conbody><section><title>Description:</title><p>Arcadia is a magical
land that roughly parallels Earth. However, where Earth is primarily
scientific and quantifiable, Arcadia is a land of magic without
any pretense of physical laws. The major inhabitants of Arcadia
are the Faerie; the elves, dwarves, gnomes, giants, dragons and
ghosts of earthly legends.</p><p>Earth and Arcadia are closely linked
mystically in that an object or place in one world is very likely
to have a parallel in the other. For example, at one spot on Earth,
there is a human city, in Arcadia there would be an elfin village
or a desolate expanse of towering rock formations. Major events
on Earth have ‘ripple effects’ or ‘echoes’ in Arcadia and vice versa.
A major war on Earth could precipitate a conflict among the Fey.</p><p>As
far as dimensional travel goes, Arcadia is fairly easy to reach
from Earth (Travel Value = 4). In some places where the link between
the two worlds is very thin (Stonehenge, Inverness etc), the Travel
Value is reduced to 2. However, dimensional shift is very chaotic
and unpredictable between these two dimensions, making regular travel
perilous. In some cases, people have been known to enter Arcadia
without even trying.</p></section>
<section><title>History:</title><p>Almost all of Earth’s legendary
Faerie folk have gone to live in Arcadia permanently. No large concentrations
of Fey have existed since the 1500s. An alternate theory proposes that
the Faerie have always lived in Arcadia and have just stopped visiting
Earth. It has since been discovered that the Faerie are somehow
related to the ancient race of Atlanteans that came from a distant
planet and settled on Earth long before humans were born. During
the Exile War, which was fought 40,000 years ago, the majority of
the Faerie population were driven from Earth by the beings known
as Protectors. Only a few Faerie were left on Earth, although they
still visited from time to time, thus giving birth to the legends
among the humans who saw them. Many things have happened to Arcadia
due to its relationship with Earth and it has given Earth heroes
such as Nightwitch, Spellbinder, Lancelot, Magus and Daniel O’Connell,
and villains such as Efferfran.</p><p>One of the most significant
events in the history of Arcadia happened during the Earth year
1950, when a human named Walter Elias Disney, a visitor to the High
Court of Arcadia, went mad and began a slaughter of the Faerie with
the help of his minions. Disney, forever after known to the Fey
as The Dark Prince, was eventually banished from the realm, but
only after he had killed many Faerie creatures, including an entire
race known as the Nairnes. The Faerie declared war on the Dark Prince
and his Empire in the Earth year 2013. Disney was eventually defeated
and killed, and the Faerie took over his Empire.</p><p>In the year
2014, the Faerie joined the Holy War on the side of the Egyptians
as they prepared to once again return to the world that they were
so long ago exiled from. In August of 2014, it became apparent to
the highest advisors of King Oberon and Queen Titania that the Holy
War would not end for the Faerie until the last Catholic was destroyed.
Knowing that this policy would be disastrous for the Faerie, Spellbinder
signed an illegal treaty with Pope Constantine II, the newly elected
Pope of the Catholic Schism. Titania and Oberon refused to ratify
this treaty and charged Spellbinder with treason. Spellbinder, Lancelot,
the Lady of the Lake, Magus, Tamlin and Nightwitch were declared
Trainna (traitor) to the Throne and were sentenced to death. With
the exception of Magus, all the traitors escaped Arcadia and Spellbinder
came to the realization that the only way to end the Holy War was
for her to usurp the Arcadian Throne. The Lady of the Lake, in her
role as the Kingmaker, declared that she had been having visions
for a very long time and declared that Spellbinder was indeed the
rightful heir to the Throne. After some fierce battles, and using
some Disney technology, Spellbinder and her companions were successful
in overthrowing Oberon and Titania, and Spellbinder become Ard Rian
(Fey for High Queen) Thrayonlosa Spellbinder of Arcadia.</p><p>Rob
Scearce created Arcadia and Adrienne Kent has contributed extensively
to it.</p></section></conbody></concept>
